

Personal Profile

As a designer for the past 20 years (as an artist past 30 years) I've had the opportunity to work for various design and web development companies.

Full cycle of web design and developing strat from wire frame to good ux/ui design mockup to full code of web standard and image optimizing for fast website loading

I have worked for Higher education, Retail, Healthcare, Beauty spa, Small businesses, Religious and Non-profit organisations.

All these experiences combined have made me a designer adn developer with the following qualities:

- Strategic thinker
- Excellent leadership and planning skills
- · Adaptable and efficient
- · Exceptional attention to detail
- · Team player and team builder
- Love for growth and learning
- · Ability to relate to cultures
- Thorough and meticulous
- · Fast and able to work under pressure
- · Capable of doing a massive range of styles rather than just my own
- · Excellent knowledge of design, typography and Web standard
- **Mobile-First, Responsive Design**
- Cross Browser Testing & Debugging



DOB: 26-05-1968 Married



Blk 53 Geylang Bahru #12-3359 Singapore - 330053



V.Ramachandran

Graphic UX UI and Web Developer



(7) +65 8233 6251



ram_vvram@yahoo.com

Experience

Apr 2017 - Till

Graphic UX UI and Web Developer TNB Wave Pte Ltd (Ad Agency) - Singapore

Design and Develop all Graphics, Web and Social Media

Graphic UX UI and Web Developer Iceberg media works Pte Ltd (Ad Agency) - Singapore

Mar 2014 - Mar 2017

Design and Develop all Graphics, Web and Social Media

Graphic\ Web Designer

Sep 2013 - Feb 2014

What to Eat Delivery Pte Ltd (Food Delivery) - Singapore

Design all Graphics, Web and Print

Graphic\ Web Designer

Sep 2007 - Mar 2013

Colourcast Bureau Pte Ltd (Printing) - Singapore

Design all Graphics, Web and Print

Graphic\ Web Designer

Sep 2006 - Aug 2007

Dec 2005 - Aug 2006

Graphic Designer

Graphic Designer

Sep 2004 - Nov 2005

Graphic Designer

Jan 2001 - Aug 2004

Graphic Designer

Aug 1999 - Dec 2000

Jan1988 - June1998

National Photo Engravers Pte Ltd (Printing) - Singapore Design and Develop all Graphic, Web and Social Media

Trend Frames Art Gallery Pte Ltd (Printing) - Singapore

Designing for Printing

Mediatron Advertising Pte Ltd (Ad Agency) - Singapore

Designing for Printing and Ads

SriRam7Graphics (Ad Agency) - India

Designing for Printing and Ads

Supreme Scanners Pte Ltd (Printing) - India

Designing for Printing

Indian Army, India

Worked as Draftsman and Artist

Education

PGDCA (year 2000)

M.A (year 1998)

Diploma in Fine Arts (year 1988)

Wizard Soft Tech - India Annamalai University - India Santhanus Chitra Vidyalam - India

Skills

Software

Adobe Creative Cloud

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign
- Dreamweaver
- After Effect
- Flash

Sketch

Freehand

Programme

- (
- lava

Web front end

- Html5
- · CSS3
- JavaScript

Frame works

- Bootstrap
- Foundation
- jQuery
- AngularJS
- · Node Js

Web back end

- php
- MySqli

CMS

Wordpress

- Custom theme
- PSD to WP
- HTML to WP

Others

Freehand Drawing

Painting Water

- Oil
- Acrylic